Theresa Hoffmann

User Experience Researcher

Pittsburgh, PA | theresahoffmann.ux@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/theresahoffmann | resihoff.github.io/portfolio-website

UX Researcher with a background in English literature and PR. Skilled in user research and testing, including surveying, interviewing, and usability testing. Experienced in translating research findings into actionable insights.

PROJECTS

HandCrafted, UX/UI Designer & Researcher

May 2022

Created an e-commerce site that makes web3 accessible to everyone. Within 6 days, conducted a user survey, secondary
research, and competitor analysis to assess the problem space, then designed, tested, and revised a prototype. Successfully
submitted the finished product and a presentation thereof to the judges of the Avocademy Designathon.

PlantPeople, UX/UI Designer & Researcher

November 2021-June 2022

 Built an app that connects hobby gardeners with plant experts for tips and advice. Cycled the project through the User-Centered Design Process from Discovery to Prototype and Test, serving as lead researcher and designer over the course of the project. Created a clickable prototype ready for hand-off to developers.

SKILLS & TOOLS

User-Centered Design Methodology, User Research, User Personas, User Flows, Card Sorting, Information Architecture, Wireframing, Prototyping, UI Design, UX Writing, Usability Testing, App Design, Web Design, Agile Methodology, Oral and Written Communication

Adobe XD, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Figma, Balsamiq, Marvel, LucidChart, Optimal Workshop, Survey Monkey, MS Office, Google Workspace, Dropbox, Atom, GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, FigJam, Miro, Trello, Notion

Fluent native speaker of German

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX Research Team Co-Lead, Tech Fleet

August 2022-Present

• Lead the research team testing the progressive web app designed to replace the current The Serious Type website. Guide a team of 6 research apprentices through usability testing and other user research and secondary research relating to social media use among Gen Z, safety and mental health concerns of existing platforms and how to reimagine social media.

UX Research Apprentice, Tech Fleet

May 2022-July 2022

Increase user engagement for The Serious Type, a social platform for teens to share creative work. Conducted a competitor
analysis, user interviews, user surveys, secondary research, and multiple card sorts to understand the problem space and
better meet users wants and needs. Designed a progressive web app to replace the current The Serious Type website.

Account Executive, RW Jones Agency

March 2019-May 2021

- Improved positive media presence of multiple clients while managing various issues faced by those clients. Managed 3 client
 accounts while serving on several other client accounts in support role. Guided clients' internal and external communications
 strategies during the global COVID-19 pandemic and assisted one client with a leadership transition during this crisis.
 Increased positive visibility of clients, including placements in NPR, The Washington Post, The Hill, POLITICO, and other
 national media outlets, and secured additional business from 2 clients.
- Maintained company brand and build the agency's national reputation. Managed production of monthly media planner for clients. Copyedited and produced layout of monthly newsletter for clients. Assisted in managing the RWJ blog, podcast, and website. Produced email marketing campaigns to clients. Elevated the reputation of RWJ and the premier PR agency serving

higher education and consistently published content on deadline for my entire tenure.

Account Coordinator, Dick Jones Communications/RW Jones Agency

June 2016-March 2019

- Supported media relations efforts on behalf of 5-7 clients at any given time while marketing the firm itself. Crafted and
 executed hundreds of national media campaigns on behalf of clients, including op-ed writing, national political poll data
 releases during presidential and mid-term elections, and publicizing research and expertise of faculty. Improved national
 visibility of several clients.
- Crafted a new brand identity for the agency and socialize that identity among existing and prospective clients. Devised a new
 brand identity including logo ideas, color scheme, and fonts. Created all new branded materials, including templates for
 presentations and both client-facing and internal documents. Assisted in management and rebuild of company website. Wrote
 inbound marketing content. Successfully executed agency's rebrand without losing clients.

Leasing Agent, Alvern Gardens Apartments, Prudential Realty Company

August 2013-May 2016

- Secured leases of several vacant apartments on a property boasting more than 100 units. Responded to email and phone
 leads of potential renters as they were received. Gave apartment tours to both scheduled visitors and walk-ins. Processed
 rental applications and other sensitive documents. Substantially reduced the number of vacancies on the property to the point
 of having a waiting list for vacancies for the first time in years.
- Redesigned model apartment on a small budget. Took inventory of materials, including furniture and décor. Assisted in the
 selection of new kitchen finishes, paint colors, and carpet color. Hunted for deals and purchased new furniture and décor as
 needed, while repurposing existing materials as available. Took model apartment from a 1980s aesthetic to a universally
 appealing modern, contemporary aesthetic that made rooms feel bigger and more open and allowed prospective renters to
 better envision themselves living on the property.
- Assisted property manager in day-to-day operations of leasing office. Secured and recorded rent payments from residents.
 Interpreted and passed along maintenance requests to maintenance crew. Produced monthly newsletter and managed PRC blog. Handled the distribution of pool passes to residents each summer. Assisted in move-in and move-out procedures Improved living conditions on the property.

Freelance Writer, University of Pittsburgh at Bradford Communications & Marketing

June 2013-August 2013

• Contributed content for a special publication celebrating the 50th anniversary of the University of Pittsburgh at Bradford. Contacted alumni, conducted phone interviews with them, wrote and edited articles about their experiences at the institution and their lives since graduating. Successfully produced 7 articles that were printed in the 50th anniversary publication.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry User Experience Design Certificate (September 2022)

Intensive project-based online training program with a focus on user experience design, user research, user interface design, and frontend development.

Duquesne University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (May 2016)

Master of Arts in English Literature with a Concentration in Writing and Media Technology

Cook Honors College (CHC) at Indiana University of Pennsylvania (IUP), Indiana, Pennsylvania (May 2013)

Bachelor of Arts in English Writing and Film Studies, summa cum laude